Raynad Chishty

Email: raynad36@gmail.com
Phone: 703-303-3091

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rayc06/
Personal Site: rchishty.info

Statement:

An adaptable and flexible student with expertise in programming, machine learning, developing algorithms, and solving complex problems. I seek to apply my programming and algorithmic skills in a fast-paced environment where I am challenged to think outside the box, achieve goals, and expand my knowledge on various topics of diverse difficulty.

Education:

- Academies of Loudoun High School (2020 Present)
 Academy of Engineering & Technology (AET)
- Potomac Falls High School (2020 Present)
- Northern Virginia Community College (2022 2023)
- Grade: 12
- Current courses: AET AP Calculus BC, AET AP Chemistry, AET Senior Research (capstone project), AP Comparative Government and Politics, DE ENG 246 American Literature 1, AP Statistics

Skills:

- **Programming Experience:** Java (3 years), HTML, CSS, Python (2 years)
- Applications: Microsoft Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Unqork, Repl.it, Microsoft PowerPoint/Word/Excel, Adobe Photoshop/After Effects/Acrobat, Anaconda Navigator

Employment History:

• Chainbridge Solutions (July 2023 – August 2023)

As a software developer intern through the Summer CCI Cybersecurity Internship program, I Replicated an employee onboarding app in an unknown no-code environment to explore its uses and benefits, then presented a final app, it's framework, and the process I used, to a panel of employees.

• **Cyber Commonwealth Initiative** (June 2023 – July 2023)

Attended a two-week professional skills boot camp as a part of the Summer CCI Cybersecurity Internship, where training was given on workplace interactions and common cybersecurity issues, threats, and information.

• **C2 Education** (May 2023 – Present)

Worked as a computer science tutor, assisting peers with assignments and unfamiliar topics. Learned to work with individuals of differing personalities and adapt to their learning styles. Also strengthened my Java skills through mentoring and tutoring.

• **Kiwa Korean Grill** (May 2023 – August 2023)

Worked as a Summer Korean barbeque server. Responsible for serving and cooking food, customer satisfaction, store cleanliness, and speed.

• Starbucks Corporation (April 2022 – May 2023)

Worked as a Starbucks barista, promoted Starbucks's culture, values, and missions, provided excellent customer service to all guests, and mastered working under pressure and maintaining a calm demeanor. Also, capable of handling and prioritizing multiple tasks under pressure, including preparing beverages and food products and managing a cash register.

Promotion: Promoted to Barista Trainer within a few months of employment due to leadership and mentoring skills.

• **Ion International Training Center** (July 2021 – March 2022)

Worked as a Front desk receptionist and skate guard/ice monitor, ensuring customers had a smooth experience while selecting skates, a safe environment on the ice, a fast, concise encounter when asking questions, and an enjoyable experience.

Notable Projects:

- Designed part of a mission to Mars as a Systems Manager of the mission transit team at the NASA Langley Research Center, part of the Virginia Aerospace Science and Technology Scholars (VASTS) Summer Academy program. As a Systems Manager of the Mission Transit team, I was responsible for overseeing the team's progress and success in developing an effective method of transportation to and from Mars. Also served as a representative for the team in meetings and panel discussions.
- Created a graphical presentation using Adobe After Effects, utilizing particle systems, physics, expressions, and motion graphics to display data, results, and findings for a math project.
- Created a machine learning project using TensorFlow and Python with the ability to predict the survivability of individuals on board the Titanic as a computer science project.
- Wrote a technical report in APA Style that focused on and analyzed the mistakes and Engineering Ethics Violations
 engineers made that led to the Challenger STS 51-L Accident, "The Challenger Disaster," for VASTS (Virginia Aerospace
 Science and Technology Scholars).
- Created a personal website on GitHub Pages using React.js, entailing personal information and extracurriculars.

Extra-Curriculars:

- Computer Science Honor Society Member (2021 Present)
- Ashburn Xtreme Ice Hockey Tier 2 Travel (2019 2021)
- Loudoun Knights Ice Hockey Tier 2 Travel (2021 2022)
- Potomac Falls/Dominion Ice Hockey (2020 Present)
- Virginia Aerospace Science and Technology Scholars (VASTS) Summer Academy (July 2023)